Finding Aid for Carl M. Saunders papers, 1915-1964
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Carl M. Saunders papers 1915-1964
Saunders, Carl M. (Carl Maxon), 1890-1974.
1 linear foot and 1 oversize volume
85362 Aa 2; AC
Newspaper editor of the Grand Rapids Herald and the Jackson Citizen Patriot; personal and professional papers.
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The collection was the gift of Saunders family members (donor no. 5861 ) and came to the library in 1976.
The collection is open to research.
Carl M. Saunders was born October 26, 1890 in Grand Rapids, Michigan. Following graduation from high school, he began his newspaper career as a reporter for the Grand Rapids News (1909). He then moved to the Kalamazoo Telegraph-Press (1911), becoming managing editor in 1912. He was copy editor for the Detroit Free Press (1913-14). The bulk of his career was spent in Grand Rapids and Kalamazoo, Michigan. He served as editorial writer for the Grand Rapids Herald, 1915-1928, associate editor, 1928-1932, and then editor, 1932-1933. In 1934, Saunders became editor of the Jackson Citizen Patriot where he remained until his retirement in 1961. Throughout his career, Saunders was member of many professional and civic organizations. In 1949, he was the recipient of the Pulitzer Prize for editorial writing. He died October 2, 1974.
The collection consists of correspondence, including many letters from Michigan Senator Arthur Vandenberg, scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, and photographs concerning his newspaper career.
Subjects:
American newspapers--Michigan--Jackson.; American newspapers--Michigan--Grand Rapids.; Grand Rapids herald (1892); Jackson citizen patriot.; Journalists--Michigan--Jackson.; Journalists--Michigan--Grand Rapids.
Contributors:
Vandenberg, Arthur H. (Arthur Hendrick), 1884-1951.
Genre Terms:
Scrapbooks.
- Newspaper career
  - Autobiography (Box 1)
  - Correspondence
    - Undated and 1915-1933 (Box 1)
    - 1945 (Box 1)
    - 1947-1964 (Box 1)
  - Correspondence with Arthur Vandenberg, 1919-1951 (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning Arthur Vandenberg (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning Saunders' nomination for a Brotherhood Media award (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning trip to Europe, 1945, 3 folders (Box 1)
  - Papers concerning retirement, 1961 (Box 1)
  - Miscellaneous papers, 2 folders (Box 1)
  - Photographs, 5 folders (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook concerning Saunders' nomination for a Pulitzer Prize, 1949 (Volume 1)
    (oversize volume)